Joshua Benjamin

340 E. Chestnut St., Lancaster, PA, 17602 Phone: 717.538.0866 | Email: joshuasevendavid@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-benjamin-046a7196/

GitHub: https://github.com/jbenj-upenn

Web Development Portfolio: https://jbenj-upenn.github.io/personal-profile-v2020/

Professional Summary

I have experience as a functional software consultant with invenioLSI implementing SAP software in its Student Lifecycle Management (SLcM) module, maintaining an eye toward ABAP code mastery. I thoroughly enjoy learning and working in Enterprise Resource Planning software. I continue to explore different modules in SAP's ERP solution and have begun to learn Acumatica.

Additionally, I have training and experience as a Front-End and Back-End Web Developer (computer coding) and a background in Linguistics and Education; all of these allow me to create richer and more meaningful experiences for app and website users. I received a full-stack (MERN technologies, see *Technical Skills* below) certificate from the University of Pennsylvania. In terms of computer coding, I look forward to potentially working in a collaborative environment with other developers on a variety of challenging, socially-inspiring, and rewarding projects.

Technical Skills

Software/Development Languages: HTML, CSS (and various CSS frameworks like Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, etc.), JavaScript, jQuery, API client-side server calls (AJAX), HTTP calls, JSON, Node.JS and NPM packages, MySql/Sequelize, Mongo/Mongoose, ReactJS, JAVA, PHP (WordPress), Squarespace, ABAP, GIT, Github, CLI, SAP/ABAP.

Coding Projects of Note

Professional: Szilagyi Law LLC

Deployed Website: https://www.szilagyilawllc.com/

- A website developed for a new law firm in Lancaster City, PA for Attorney Adam Szilagyi.
- Via Squarespace, the site also has custom HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in addition to SEO attributes.

Breaking Bread

Github: https://github.com/ksmera01/Breaking-Bread

Deployed Project: https://breaking-bread-donate.herokuapp.com/

- A full-stack app designed to link individuals or organizations with hunger-related needs with individuals or organizations with the ability to meet those needs.
- In working remotely with my three team members, our roles often overlapped. I was
 primarily focused on the front-end of the project, handling appearance and
 responsiveness using Handlebars and CSS languages.

Covid Activities

Github: https://github.com/jbenj-upenn/CovidActivities

Deployed Project: https://jbenj-upenn.github.io/CovidActivities/

- A front-end app designed to allow users to search APIs for new recipes to try at home or new books to read and discuss with other users.
- Working remotely with my three team members, all of our roles overlapped during this project, utilizing JavaScript for the most part, as well as CSS and HTML.

Goal Getter

Github: https://github.com/mnicolai20/GoalGetter

Deployed Project: https://goal-getters.herokuapp.com/

- A full-stack app designed to connect users with similar goals as well as simply allow users to describe and save their goals, deleting them when they have been achieved.
- Working remotely with my three team members, I handled the front-end technology using ReactJS.

Experience

- Help Desk Tech Support, Level 1 and 2, Michael Management, 2022-present
 - Handle password resets, role request, and other basic access-related queries via chat, email, and the Help Desk
 - Communicate between users and First Basis consultants to achieve results leading to users' success
 - Update, edit, and contribute to SAP Access FAQs
 - Help manage and contribute to SAP Access Twitter profile
- Associate Student Lifecycle Management (SLcM) Consultant, invenioLSI, 2021-2022

Client: United States Air Force implementing SAP's SLcM module

- Assist the project team in documenting the development of solutions for clients
- Assist in reviewing, evaluating, and discussing application and/or technical architectures
- Assist team effort in preparing solution documents
- Complete assignments punctually, meet deadlines, and keep commitments to the team
- Comply with administrative responsibilities punctually
- Keep manager informed of workload and concerns
- Develop a deeper understanding of SAP methodologies, tools, standards, and techniques
- Assist with project documentation
- Demonstrate effective organizational skills

- Prioritize activities correctly in accordance with project plans
- Demonstrate the ability to accomplish project assignments resulting in quality service

• English Adjunct Professor, Drexel University, 2010-2021

- Planned and carried out a variety of courses in the First-Year Writing Program
- Maintained student records for evaluation
- Held office hours for guidance and collaboration with students
- Attended meetings and participated in formal and informal professional development

• English Adjunct Professor, University of Pennsylvania, 2013-2020

- Planned and carried out a variety of courses in the English Language Program
- Maintained student records for evaluation
- Held office hours for guidance and collaboration with students
- Attended meetings and participated in formal and informal professional development

• English Adjunct Professor, Millersville University, 2016-2017

- Planned and carried out a Transformational Grammar course
- Maintained student records for evaluation
- Held office hours for guidance and collaboration with students

• English Adjunct Professor, Harrisburg Area Community College, 2012-2013

- Planned and carried out a variety of courses in reading and writing for non-native English- speakers
- Maintained student records for evaluation
- o Held office hours for guidance and collaboration with students
- Attended meetings and participated in formal and informal professional development

• Spanish Teacher/English as a Second Language Teacher, La Academia, 2009-2010

- Planned and carried out a Spanish class as well as several English classes; used a "push-in" model to assist non-native English-speaking students in the classroom
- Maintained student records for evaluation
- Attended faculty meetings and participated in formal and informal professional development

• **Spanish Teacher,** Living Word Academy, 2003-2008

- Plan and carry out classes for all five levels of high school Spanish
- Maintained student records for evaluation
- Attended faculty meetings and participated in formal and informal professional development

• Bartender, Lancaster Country Club, 2021

- Efficiently and cordially prepared beverages for customers
- Bartender, Ciro's Italian Bistro, 2021
 - Efficiently and cordially prepared beverages for customers

- Serve tables taking food and beverage orders
- Deliver food and drinks efficiently
- Maintain clean workstations before and after shift
- Assist co-workers as needed
- Bartender, Stoner's Grille, 2018-2020
 - Efficiently and cordially prepared beverages for customers
- Bartender, Federal Taphouse, 2016-2019
 - o Efficiently and cordially prepared beverages for customers
- Bartender, Spring House, 2021-Present
 - Efficiently and cordially prepare beverages for customers
- Freelance Muralist/Artist, 2000-Present
 - o Develop and execute professional murals for commissioned projects

Education

- University of Pennsylvania/Trilogy Educational Services, 2020- Philadelphia, PA; received certificate as a full-stack computer developer, having covered HTML; CSS and CSS frameworks (e.g., Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize); JavaScript; jQuery; Web, Third-Party, and Server-Side APIs; NodeJs and its common packages (e.g., Express, FS); MySQL and Sequelize; Mongo and Mongoose; and ReactJS.
- West Chester University, 2010- West Chester, PA; earned a Master's degree in TESL (Teaching English as a Second Language); Cumulative GPA- 4.0/4.0
- Millersville University, 2003- Millersville, PA; earned a double major Bachelor's degree
 in Advanced English Linguistics and ESL (English as a Second Language) with a
 Spanish minor; Cumulative GPA- 3.54/4.0